Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod. My name is Marco.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and a very Merry Christmas to everyone.
我是Catherine，祝大家圣诞快乐！
That's right, Merry Christmas. We are at that time again where we are celebrating Christmas,
没错，圣诞快乐。又到了我们庆祝圣诞节的时候了，
we're having dinner with family and friends, we're giving presents and of course,
我们和家人朋友共进晚餐，互赠礼物，当然，
there are some other traditions that come into play like for example Santa Claus.
还有一些其他传统，比如圣诞老人。
Santa Claus. So, we've got a very special advanced level lesson for you today.
圣诞老人。所以，今天我们为你准备了一节非常特别的高级课程。
We've got a poem. It's a very traditional poem that is read or listened to on the holiday
我们有一首诗。这是一首非常传统的诗，在节日期间人们会朗读或聆听，
and we're going to talk a little bit about some of the interesting words and phrases that are used in this.
我们将讨论其中一些有趣的单词和短语。
But first off, let's just listen to the poem itself.
但首先，让我们先听一下这首诗本身。
It was the night before Christmas when all through the house, not a creature was stirring, not even a mouse.
那是圣诞前夜，整栋房子里，没有一个生灵在动，连老鼠也不例外。
The stockings were hung by the chimney with care in hopes that St. Nicholas soon would be there.
长袜被小心翼翼地挂在烟囱旁，希望圣尼古拉斯很快会到来。
The children were nestled all snug in their beds while visions of sugar plums danced in their heads
孩子们安详地躺在温暖的床上，脑海里飞舞着糖梅的幻影，
and mysterious sounds of bells and bells were heard in the air.
空气中传来神秘而清脆的铃铛声。
The children were nestled all snug in their beds while visions of sugar plums danced in their heads
孩子们安详地躺在温暖的床上，脑海里飞舞着糖梅的幻影，
and Mama in her kerchief and I in my cap had just settled down for a long winter's nap.
妈妈戴着头巾，我戴着睡帽，刚准备开始漫长的冬夜睡眠。
When out on the lawn there arose such a clatter, I sprang from the bed to see what was the matter.
这时，外面的草坪上突然传来一阵嘈杂声，我跳下床去看发生了什么事。
Away to the window I flew like a flash, tore open the shutters and threw open the sash.
我像闪电一样冲到窗前，猛地拉开百叶窗，推开了窗框。
The snow and snow gave the luster of midday to objects below when what to my wondering eyes should appear
雪和雪让下面的物体闪耀着正午般的光泽，这时，我惊奇的眼睛看到了什么，
but a miniature sleigh, an eight tiny reindeer with a little old driver so lively and quick
却是一辆微型雪橇，八只小小的驯鹿，还有一个活泼敏捷的小老头，
I knew in a moment it must be St. Nick.
我立刻知道那一定是圣尼克。
More rapid than eagles his coursers they came and he whistled and shouted and called them by name.
他的骏马比鹰还快，他吹着口哨，大声喊着它们的名字。
Now Dasher, now Dancer, now Prancer and Vixen, on Comet, on Cupid, on Donder and Blitzen,
现在，Dasher，现在，Dancer，现在，Prancer和Vixen，冲啊，Comet，冲啊，Cupid，冲啊，Donder和Blitzen，
to the top of the porch, to the top of the wall, now dash away, dash away, dash away all.
冲到门廊顶上，冲到墙顶上，现在，快冲，快冲，全都冲啊！
As dry leaves that before the wild hurricanes fly, when they meet with an obstacle, mount to the sky.
就像枯叶在狂野的飓风前飞舞，当它们遇到障碍时，便升向天空。
So up to the housetop the coursers they flew with the sleighs full of toys and St. Nicholas too.
于是，骏马们飞上了屋顶，雪橇里装满了玩具，还有圣尼古拉斯。
And then in a twinkling I heard on the roof the prancing and pawing of each little hoof.
然后，转眼间，我听到屋顶上传来每只小蹄子的跳跃和刨地声。
As I drew in my head and was turning around, down the chimney St. Nicholas came with a bound.
当我缩回头转过身时，圣尼古拉斯一下子从烟囱里跳了下来。
He was dressed all in fur from his head to his toe and his clothes were all tarnished with ashes and soot.
他从头到脚都穿着毛皮，衣服上沾满了灰烬和煤烟。
A bundle of toys he had flung on his back and he looked like a peddler just opening his pack.
他背上背着一捆玩具，看起来就像一个刚打开包裹的小贩。
His eyes, how they twinkled, his dimples, how merry.
他的眼睛，多么闪亮，他的酒窝，多么欢快。
His cheeks were like roses, his nose like a cherry.
他的脸颊像玫瑰，鼻子像樱桃。
His droll little mouth was drawn up in a bow and the beard of his chin was as white as the snow.
他那滑稽的小嘴弯成弓形，下巴上的胡子像雪一样白。
The stump of a pipe he held tight in his teeth and the smoke had encircled his head like a wreath.
他嘴里紧紧叼着烟斗的残端，烟雾像花环一样环绕着他的头。
He had a broad face and a little round belly that shook when he laughed like a bowl full of jelly.
他有一张宽阔的脸和一个小小的圆肚子，笑起来时像一碗果冻一样晃动。
He was chubby and plump, a right old jolly elf, and I laughed when I saw him in spite of myself.
他胖乎乎的，圆滚滚的，真是个快乐的老精灵，我忍不住笑了起来。
A wink of his eye and a twist of his head soon gave me to know I had nothing to dread.
他眨了眨眼，歪了歪头，立刻让我明白我没什么好怕的。
He spoke not a word but went straight to work and filled all the stockings then turned with a jerk.
他一句话没说，直接开始工作，把所有的长袜都装满，然后猛地转过身。
And laying his finger aside of his nose and giving a nod, up the chimney he rose.
他把手指放在鼻子旁边，点了点头，然后从烟囱里升了上去。
He sprang to his sleigh, to his team gave a whistle, and away they all flew like the down of a thistle.
他跳上雪橇，向他的队伍吹了声口哨，然后它们就像蓟花冠毛一样飞走了。
But I heard him exclaim, ere as he drove out of sight,
但我听到他喊道，在他驶出视线之前，
Happy Christmas to all and to all a good night!
祝大家圣诞快乐，晚安！
Alright, we're back. So, the poem is very nice. It's long.
好了，我们回来了。这首诗很美，也很长。
And just to kind of recap what the poem is talking about, what is the general story of the poem?
为了回顾一下这首诗的内容，它大致讲了一个什么故事？
The story of the poem is that Santa Claus is coming to visit someone's house.
这首诗的故事是圣诞老人来拜访某人的家。
And there's a person in the story who is watching Santa Claus arrive.
故事里有一个人正在看着圣诞老人到来。
And he's seeing Santa Claus take the reindeer up onto the roof, come down the chimney,
他看到圣诞老人把驯鹿带到屋顶上，从烟囱下来，
and lay the presents out for the children, filling the stockings as well.
为孩子们摆放礼物，也把长袜装满。
Okay, so it's basically a nice poetic description of Santa Claus.
好的，所以这基本上是对圣诞老人一个优美的诗意描述。
And also, it goes in to describe in a very nice way the way Santa Claus looks like.
而且，它还以非常优美的方式描述了圣诞老人的样子。
It's very descriptive. We have descriptions of what Santa Claus looks like, what he's wearing, his smile, how he's a little bit fat.
描述性很强。我们看到了对圣诞老人外貌、穿着、笑容、以及他有点胖的描述。
We also have descriptions of the animals, the special animals that we hear about so often that are called reindeer.
我们还描述了动物，那些我们经常听说的特殊动物，叫做驯鹿。
Alright, so we've divided up the poem by lines, so then it's going to be easier for you to go to the line that we're talking about.
好的，我们按行划分了这首诗，这样你就能更容易地找到我们正在讨论的那一行。
Let's start with the first line, with this first word that's actually very interesting.
让我们从第一行开始，这个第一个词其实非常有趣。
"'Twas the night before Christmas when all through the house."
“那是圣诞前夜，整栋房子里。”
So what does this first word mean?
那么，这第一个词是什么意思？
"'Twas' is an abbreviation, so it's a shortened version of, it was.
“'Twas”是一个缩写，是“it was”的简写形式。
Okay, so, but do you actually use this now if you're writing?
好的，那么，你现在写作时会用这个词吗？
No, this is not something I would use now in writing, and it's not something I would say.
不，我现在写作不会用这个词，我也不会说这个词。
It's actually more of an archaic form, something that you might hear in poetry or historical writing.
它其实更像是一种古语形式，你可能会在诗歌或历史作品中听到。
Okay, so it was the night before Christmas, right? So we're talking about December 24th.
好的，所以是圣诞前夜，对吧？我们说的是12月24日。
The night of December 24th, that's right.
12月24日的夜晚，没错。
Alright, so the first two lines talk about how it was the night before Christmas and in the house there was nothing stirring, not even a mouse.
好的，所以前两行说的是圣诞前夜，房子里没有动静，连老鼠都没有。
So not even the smallest little animal, so it's very quiet in the house is what's happening.
所以连最小的动物都没有，房子里非常安静。
So now we jump to line number seven, where the poet describes, "'And Mama in her kerchief and I in my cap.'"
现在我们跳到第七行，诗人描述道：“妈妈戴着头巾，我戴着睡帽。”
So we know that the person talking is the dad, because he's talking about himself and Mama, mother.
所以我们知道说话的人是爸爸，因为他提到了自己和妈妈。
They're in bed together.
他们一起躺在床上。
"'And Mama in her kerchief and I in my cap.'" So I'm wearing a nightcap, a cover on my head, it's like a hat.
“妈妈戴着头巾，我戴着睡帽。”所以我戴着睡帽，头上盖着东西，就像一顶帽子。
"'And Mama has a kerchief.'"
“妈妈戴着头巾。”
What's a kerchief?
什么是头巾？
A kerchief is another abbreviation, it's short for handkerchief.
头巾是另一个缩写，是“handkerchief”的简称。
Okay.
好的。
And a handkerchief is a piece of fabric or cloth that sometimes we use for our noses when we have to blow our nose.
手帕是一块布料或织物，有时我们用来擦鼻子。
But also you can use a kerchief in your hair to cover your hair.
但也可以把头巾戴在头发上遮住头发。
Okay, so if you can imagine it, this must take place, I don't know, maybe 50, 60 years ago
好的，所以你可以想象，这一定发生在，我不知道，也许五六十年前，
when dads used to wear hats to bed and women also handkerchiefs on their heads.
那时爸爸们戴着帽子睡觉，女人们也戴着头巾。
Maybe 200 years ago when people wore these long night hats, nightcaps.
也许是200年前，人们戴着这种长长的睡帽。
The pajamas and everything.
还有睡衣什么的。
All right, now let's jump over to line 18 and 19 when he's talking about the reindeer and the sleigh arriving
好了，现在我们跳到第18和19行，他谈到驯鹿和雪橇到达时，
and he says, "'I knew in a moment it must be Saint Nick.'" This is another way of calling Santa Claus, right?
他说：“我立刻知道那一定是圣尼克。”这是称呼圣诞老人的另一种方式，对吧？
Saint Nicholas is his name, but you also call him Claus or Santa Claus.
圣尼古拉斯是他的名字，但你也叫他克劳斯或圣诞老人。
Okay, and then he said, "'More rapid than eagles, his coursers they came.'"
好的，然后他说：“‘比鹰还快，他的驯鹿来了。’”
So the word order is a bit strange here. This is common in poetry.
所以这里的词序有点奇怪。这在诗歌中很常见。
We could also say, "'His coursers came more rapidly than eagles.' They were very, very fast."
我们也可以说：“‘他的驯鹿比鹰还快。’它们非常非常快。”
But what are these coursers? We're talking about the animals pulling Santa Claus.
但这些“coursers”是什么？我们说的是拉圣诞老人的动物。
And what are those animals again?
那些动物又叫什么？
They're called reindeer.
它们叫驯鹿。
Reindeer. So the reindeer are very, very fast.
驯鹿。所以驯鹿非常非常快。
Okay, that's right because he's making the comparison about how fast eagles are compared to them.
好的，没错，因为他是在比较它们和鹰的速度。
And we hear their names, right?
我们听到了它们的名字，对吧？
Exactly. He goes on to say, "'Now Dasher, now Dancer, now Prancer.'"
没错。他接着说：“‘现在冲吧，达舍，现在跳吧，丹瑟，现在腾跃吧，普兰瑟。’”
And all of their names, Vixen, Comet, Cupid, Donder, and Blitzen.
还有它们所有的名字：维森、彗星、丘比特、唐德和布利岑。
All eight reindeer. Each animal has its own name.
一共八只驯鹿。每只动物都有自己的名字。
That's right. So all eight reindeer. Actually, we're missing one though that's very common nowadays.
没错。所以是八只驯鹿。实际上，我们少了一只，现在很常见的那只。
The reindeer that goes in the front lighting, illuminating the sky.
那只在前面照亮天空的驯鹿。
Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer. You might know the song, "'Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer.'"
红鼻子鲁道夫。你可能知道那首歌，“‘红鼻子鲁道夫。’”
That's right. So there are actually nine reindeer nowadays,
没错。所以现在实际上有九只驯鹿，
but I guess this story was before the Rudolph story came out.
但我想这个故事是在鲁道夫的故事出现之前。
This is interesting because those are the names of all the reindeer.
这很有趣，因为那是所有驯鹿的名字。
Now, I'm not sure in which order they are. I don't know who's in the back, who's in the front.
现在，我不确定它们的顺序。我不知道谁在后面，谁在前面。
I don't know either, but it's important to know that they're very fast,
我也不知道，但重要的是它们非常快，
and they come down, and then they go up.
它们下来，然后又上去。
They have to take Saint Nicholas to the roof of the house, on top of the house.
它们得把圣尼古拉斯带到房子的屋顶上，房子顶上。
That's right. So now he arrives to the top of the house, line 32.
没错。所以现在他到了屋顶，第32行。
We see, down the chimney, Saint Nicholas came with a bound.
我们看到，从烟囱下来，圣尼古拉斯一跃而下。
He came quickly, down the chimney, boom.
他很快地下来，从烟囱，砰的一声。
And at the end, he's all dressed in fur from his head to his foot.
最后，他全身从头到脚都穿着毛皮。
So top to bottom, he has fur on.
所以从上到下，他都穿着毛皮。
That's right. And I think he's got fur because he lives in the North Pole, right?
没错。我想他穿毛皮是因为他住在北极，对吧？
That's right. And it's very cold where Santa Claus lives, so he has to wear these clothes that are very warm.
没错。圣诞老人住的地方很冷，所以他得穿这些很暖和的衣服。
Okay. And obviously, since he is going up and down chimneys in line 34, we see,
好的。显然，因为他要上下烟囱，在第34行，我们看到，
and his clothes were tarnished with ashes and soot.
他的衣服被灰烬和煤烟弄脏了。
So to tarnish or tarnish means dirty.
所以“tarnish”或“tarnished”意思是脏了。
Something is tarnished if it's dirty.
如果东西脏了，就是被“tarnished”了。
So his clothes, his fur clothes were dirty with ashes and soot.
所以他的衣服，他的毛皮衣服被灰烬和煤烟弄脏了。
This means that, you know, in your fireplace, when the fire is gone, there's some gray and black stuff.
这意味着，你知道，在你的壁炉里，当火熄灭后，会有一些灰色和黑色的东西。
And that's what's on Santa Claus' clothes.
那就是圣诞老人衣服上的东西。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So, and then we go on to line 35, a bundle of toys he had flung on his back.
然后我们继续到第35行，他背上背着一捆玩具。
And he looked like a peddler just opening his pack.
他看起来像个刚打开包裹的小贩。
All right, a peddler. Now, this is not just something we talk about on Christmas.
好的，小贩。这可不是只在圣诞节才提到的东西。
You know, we have peddlers all year round.
你知道，我们一年四季都有小贩。
What are peddlers? What do they do?
什么是小贩？他们做什么？
Basically, they go around selling things.
基本上，他们到处卖东西。
So maybe you see them in a small market or sometimes in different places and maybe, I don't know, on the streets.
所以你可能在小市场里看到他们，或者有时在不同的地方，也许，我不知道，在街上。
You see them selling little things like toys or combs or books, something like that.
你看到他们卖小东西，比如玩具、梳子或书，诸如此类。
Oranges, you see fruit peddlers, people who sell fruit.
橙子，你看到水果小贩，卖水果的人。
Or you can see those watch peddlers.
或者你可以看到那些手表小贩。
You know, they say, would you like a Rolex watch? That's a watch peddler.
你知道，他们说，想要一块劳力士手表吗？那就是手表小贩。
So that's what they do, right? They're informal salesmen.
所以那就是他们做的，对吧？他们是非正式的销售员。
They don't have a store. They work on the street.
他们没有商店。他们在街上工作。
So this is why Santa looks like a peddler.
所以这就是为什么圣诞老人看起来像个小贩。
He isn't in a store. He has a bag.
他不在商店里。他有一个袋子。
And he says, look in my bag.
他说，看看我的袋子。
Right, exactly.
对，没错。
From line 37, we go on to describe the way Santa Claus looks like.
从第37行开始，我们继续描述圣诞老人的样子。
So he says, his eyes, how they twinkled.
所以他说，他的眼睛，多么闪烁。
His dimples, how merry.
他的酒窝，多么快乐。
Dimples are those small circles on your cheeks.
酒窝是你脸颊上的小圆圈。
So some people, when they smile, they have these small holes or circles.
所以有些人，当他们笑的时候，会有这些小洞或圆圈。
Those are dimples. They're very cute.
那些就是酒窝。它们很可爱。
That's right. So not everyone has them, right?
没错。所以不是每个人都有，对吧？
Some people, when they smile, you can see those dimples.
有些人，当他们笑的时候，你能看到那些酒窝。
All right. And his cheeks were like roses, his nose like a cherry.
好的。他的脸颊像玫瑰，鼻子像樱桃。
So we're saying that they're red.
所以我们在说它们是红色的。
They're red. They're pink.
它们是红色的。它们是粉色的。
Okay. Now in line 39, he says, his droll little mouth was drawn up like a bow.
好的。现在在第39行，他说，他那滑稽的小嘴像弓一样翘起。
Now, droll is a word that some people still use.
现在，“droll”这个词有些人还在用。
It's pretty common in places like England.
在像英格兰这样的地方很常见。
We don't use it as much in America.
我们在美国不常用。
We say funny instead.
我们改用“funny”。
But something that is droll, D-R-O-L-L, droll is funny.
但“droll”这个词，D-R-O-L-L，意思是滑稽的。
So his mouth, his face is funny looking.
所以他的嘴，他的脸看起来很滑稽。
Okay. His face is funny looking. All right.
好的。他的脸看起来很滑稽。好的。
And going on to line 45, we're describing how he was chubby and plump.
继续到第45行，我们在描述他如何圆胖和丰满。
So we're basically saying he was a little bit fat.
所以我们基本上在说他有点胖。
Yes.
是的。
Okay. A right jolly old elf.
好的。一个快乐的老精灵。
So what is an elf?
那么什么是精灵？
An elf is actually normally we talk about elves.
精灵实际上通常我们说的是精灵们。
So one elf, two elves as people, little people who help Santa.
所以一个精灵，两个精灵，作为人，帮助圣诞老人的小人。
They're mythical creatures who live in the North Pole and who make presents.
他们是住在北极、制作礼物的神话生物。
So an elf is a small creature who makes presents.
所以精灵就是制作礼物的小生物。
Okay.
好的。
Or maybe lives in the woods.
或者也可能住在森林里。
There are many different stories with elves.
关于精灵有很多不同的故事。
Right, right. Okay.
对，对。好的。
And in line 46, we say, and I laughed when I saw him in spite of myself.
在第46行，我们说，我忍不住笑了，当我看到他时。
What does he mean by in spite of myself?
他说的“忍不住”是什么意思？
This is really important and this is something we say in English all the time, in spite of myself.
这非常重要，而且是我们英语中经常说的一个短语，“忍不住”。
So I laughed in spite of myself.
所以我忍不住笑了。
So I didn't want to laugh.
所以我本来不想笑。
But I did.
但我还是笑了。
I wanted to be serious.
我想保持严肃。
But I did laugh.
但我确实笑了。
So in spite of myself, I didn't want to laugh.
所以“忍不住”的意思是，我不想笑。
I laughed anyway.
但我还是笑了。
So you say in spite of myself when you did the thing you did not want to do.
所以当你做了你不想做的事时，你会说“忍不住”。
Okay.
好的。
And finishing off, we are going towards the last three lines where we say,
最后，我们接近最后三行，我们说，
and away they all flew like the down of a thistle.
然后他们全都飞走了，像蓟花的冠毛一样。
What is a thistle?
什么是蓟花？
They're talking about the part of a flower that's a thistle.
他们说的是蓟花的一部分。
Oh, okay.
哦，好的。
So they just, they all flew away like quickly, rapidly like the little flower.
所以他们就像那样飞走了，快速、迅速地，像那朵小花一样。
Well, you know when a flower is sending its seeds out, it's down, it's white.
嗯，你知道当花朵散播种子时，它的冠毛是白色的。
So maybe if you blow on a flower with the white seeds, they blow away.
所以如果你对着有白色种子的花吹气，它们就会飞走。
That's what it looks like.
就是那个样子。
It looks like the seeds of a flower being blown away.
看起来就像花朵的种子被吹散一样。
Very easy.
很简单。
Okay.
好的。
Line 55 says, but I heard him exclaim, ere he drove out of sight.
第55行说，但我听到他喊道，在他驶出视线之前。
So this is an older way of saying, as he drove out of sight.
这是一种更古老的表达方式，意思是“当他驶出视线时”。
So as he's flying away, I can't see him anymore.
所以当他飞走时，我再也看不见他了。
Almost I can't see him anymore.
几乎看不见他了。
He exclaimed something.
他喊了些什么。
So ere means while this is happening.
所以“ere”意思是“在这发生时”。
Now this is another one of those maybe old English words that we don't use anymore, right?
这可能是另一个我们不常用的古英语词汇，对吧？
You wouldn't really use ere.
你一般不会用“ere”。
Ere I was walking to school, I saw the milkman.
在我走路去学校之前，我看到了送奶工。
No, we don't say this anymore.
不，我们现在不这么说了。
But you will find it in poetry and you might also find it in stories.
但你会在诗歌和故事中看到它。
Okay.
好的。
And line 56, he ends and this is very the famous way that this poem ends by saying,
第56行，他结束了，这首诗以非常著名的结尾方式说，
Happy Christmas to all and to all a good night.
祝大家圣诞快乐，晚安。
Yeah, this is the, and the first line of the poem are the most famous.
是的，这是这首诗最著名的开头和结尾。
Everyone knows these.
每个人都知道这些。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So a beautiful poem.
所以这是一首美丽的诗。
Why don't we listen to it one more time?
我们为什么不听一遍呢？
Twas the night before Christmas when all through the house,
那是圣诞前夜，整座房子里，
not a creature was stirring, not even a mouse.
没有一个生物在动，连老鼠也没有。
The stockings were hung by the chimney with care,
袜子被小心地挂在烟囱边，
in hopes that St. Nicholas soon would be there.
希望圣尼古拉斯很快会来。
The children were nestled all snug in their beds,
孩子们都舒适地依偎在床上，
while visions of sugar plums danced in their heads,
脑海里跳动着糖梅的幻影，
and Mama and Papa were in the garden.
妈妈和爸爸在花园里。
The children were playing in the garden,
孩子们在花园里玩耍，
and Mama and Papa were in the garden.
妈妈和爸爸在花园里。
While visions of sugar plums danced in their heads, and Mama in her kerchief,
脑海里跳动着糖梅的幻影，妈妈戴着她的头巾，
and I in my cap, had just settled down for a long winter's nap.
我戴着我的睡帽，刚准备睡个长冬觉。
When out on the lawn there arose such a clatter,
这时外面的草坪上传来一阵喧闹声，
I sprang from the bed to see what was the matter.
我从床上跳起来，看看发生了什么事。
Away to the window I flew like a flash, tore open the shutters and threw open the sash.
我像闪电一样飞到窗前，拉开百叶窗，推开窗扇。
The moon on the breast of the new fallen snow gave the luster of midday to objects below.
月光照在新落的雪上，给下面的物体带来了正午般的光泽。
When what to my wondering eyes should appear but a miniature sleigh,
当我惊奇的眼睛看到什么时，竟是一辆微型雪橇，
and eight tiny reindeer, with a little old driver, so lively and quick,
和八只小驯鹿，还有一位小巧的老车夫，那么活泼敏捷，
I knew in a moment it must be St. Nick.
我立刻知道那一定是圣尼克。
More rapid than eagles his coursers they came,
比鹰还快，他的骏马们来了，
and he whistled and shouted and called them by name.
他吹着口哨，喊着，叫着它们的名字。
Now Dasher, now Dancer, now Prancer and Vixen,
快跑，达舍！快跑，丹瑟！快跑，普兰瑟和维克森！
on Comet, on Cupid, on Donder and Blitzen.
冲啊，彗星！冲啊，丘比特！冲啊，唐德和布利岑！
To the top of the porch, to the top of the wall,
到门廊顶，到墙顶，
now dash away, dash away, dash away all.
现在冲啊，冲啊，全都冲啊！
As dry leaves that before the wild hurricanes fly,
像枯叶在狂风中飞舞，
when they meet with an obstacle, mount to the sky.
当它们遇到障碍时，就升向天空。
So up to the housetop the coursers they flew with the sleighs full of toys,
所以骏马们飞上屋顶，雪橇装满了玩具，
and St. Nicholas too.
还有圣尼古拉斯。
And then, in a twinkling, I heard on the roof,
然后，一眨眼间，我听到屋顶上，
the prancing and pawing of each little hoof.
每只小蹄子欢腾跳跃、刨地作响。
As I drew in my head and was turning around,
当我缩回头，正要转身时，
down the chimney St. Nicholas came with a bound.
圣尼古拉斯一下子从烟囱里跳了下来。
He was dressed all in fur from his head to his toe,
他从头到脚都裹着毛皮，
and his clothes were all tarnished with ashes and soot.
衣服上沾满了灰烬和煤烟。
A bundle of toys he had flung on his back,
他背上甩着一捆玩具，
and he looked like a peddler just opening his pack.
看起来像个刚打开货包的小贩。
His eyes, how they twinkled! His dimples, how merry!
他的眼睛，多么闪亮！他的酒窝，多么欢快！
His cheeks were like roses, his nose like a cherry.
他的脸颊像玫瑰，鼻子像樱桃。
His droll little mouth was drawn up in a bow,
他那滑稽的小嘴抿成弓形，
and the beard of his chin was as white as the snow.
下巴上的胡子白得像雪。
The stump of a pipe he held tight in his teeth,
他嘴里紧叼着一根烟斗的残柄，
and the smoke had encircled his head like a wreath.
烟雾像花环一样环绕着他的头。
He had a broad face and a little round belly
他有一张大脸和一个小圆肚子，
that shook when he laughed like a bowl full of jelly.
笑起来时肚子像一碗果冻般晃动。
He was chubby and plump, a right old jolly elf,
他胖乎乎、圆滚滚，真是个快乐的老精灵，
and I laughed when I saw him, in spite of myself.
我见到他时，忍不住笑了起来。
A wink of his eye and a twist of his head
他眨眨眼，歪歪头，
soon gave me to know I had nothing to dread.
立刻让我明白我没什么好怕的。
He spoke not a word, but went straight to work
他一言不发，直接开始干活，
and filled all the stockings, then turned with a jerk,
塞满了所有袜子，然后猛地转身，
and laying his finger aside of his nose
把手指放在鼻子旁边，
and giving a nod, up the chimney he rose.
点了点头，便从烟囱升了上去。
He sprang to his sleigh, to his team gave a whistle,
他跳上雪橇，朝他的队伍吹了声口哨，
and away they all flew like the down of a thistle.
他们就像蓟花冠毛一样飞走了。
But I heard him exclaim, ere as he drove out of sight,
但在他驶出视线前，我听见他喊道，
Happy Christmas to all, and to all a good night!
祝大家圣诞快乐，晚安！
It's very interesting because it's part of the American tradition of Christmas.
这非常有趣，因为它是美国圣诞节传统的一部分。
I think maybe also in other parts of the world
我想也许在世界其他地方，
the poem might be translated or also might be popular.
这首诗可能被翻译或也很受欢迎。
But you know, Santa Claus and all these things
但你知道，圣诞老人和这些东西
are traditions that are observed in some countries
是一些国家遵循的传统，
and it's very interesting to understand them.
了解它们非常有意思。
Absolutely, and I'm very curious to know about your Christmas traditions.
当然，我很好奇你们的圣诞节传统。
What do you do in your home country on Christmas Eve or on Christmas Day?
在你的祖国，圣诞夜或圣诞节那天你们做什么？
Do you know any poems like this or do you listen to this poem in translation?
你知道像这样的诗吗，或者你听过这首诗的翻译版吗？
Let us know. Our website is EnglishPod.com.
告诉我们吧。我们的网站是EnglishPod.com。
Alright guys, we'll see you there and have a Merry Christmas.
好了，各位，我们那里见，祝你们圣诞快乐。
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐。
Bye.
再见。